ALECZINDER SODHI

• Email: aleczinder.sodhi@gmail.com

· LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/aleczinder-sodhi

· **Phone:** +91 77188 90660



Certified IT Support Professional by Google. I am a Technology enthusiast in pursuit of a System Administrator Role.

ABOUT ME

I am an experienced business professional and Tech-Enthusiast aiming to define my career by utilizing my technical knowledge and problem-solving skills. While feeding my passion and curiosity of tinkering with electronics, I enjoy spreading awareness and keeping myself updated on technical news, new apps, technologies, and devices.

SKILLS

- L1 and L2 Support
- Technical Troubleshooting
- Windows/Linux Server Administration
- Backup Management
- Firewall configuration and management
- GPO/RBAC and centralized management
- DNS/DHCP/VLAN/VPN
- RDP/SSH
- Cloud Administration (Azure, AWS, GCP, VMWare)
- DRP
- AD/LDAP/OpenLDAP
- File/Print/Web Server Administration

CERTIFICATIONS



Google IT Support Specialization

Technical Support Fundamentals

The Bits and Bytes of Computer Networking

Operating Systems and You: Becoming a Power User System Administration and IT Infrastructure Services

IT Security: Defense against the digital arts



Technical Administrator Career Fit Achievement



Customer Engagement Career Fit Achievement

EXPERIENCE

SEPTEMER, 2015 – MARCH, 2019

CO-FOUNDER, HIMALAYAN BAZAAR LLP

Launched Brands like Himalayan Sutra and Yi&Mi to enable users to purchased household and consumer electronics from across the globe to their doorstep using E-Commerce. Maintain Seller Accounts with Marketplace Leaders like Amazon India, Flipkart and Paytm.

JULY, 2013 – FEBRUARY, 2015

CSA, TECH MAHINDRA BUSSINESS SERVICES

Provided customer support for UK Post-Pay for 3Global Services.

AUGUST, 2012 – JANUARY, 2013

AGM, MRPC HOT WHEELZ YAMAHA

Successfully executed branding campaigns

Completed institutional tie-ups with PCTE & PAU

Completed Corporate Tie-ups with Cinepolis Cinema, MBD Mall

Increased staff efficiency through communication improvement & Sharing product knowledge.

APRIL, 2010 – DECEMBER, 2010

RMA, JP MORGAN CHASE

As a Risk Management Analyst for Credit cards Maintained merit ranks in Decision Quality Accessed risk of fraud on consumer accounts and taking necessary actions to prevent theft in any way on the account.

JUNE, 2009 - MARCH, 2010

SR. CSA, SUTHERLAND GLOBAL SERVICES

Reflected exceptional performance as a Sr. CSA in windows 7- Pilot batch.

Performed with highest resolution rate, providing technical support and maintaining 100 percent customer satisfaction.

Troubleshooting and Resolving L1 and L2 Operating System issues extensively.

JUNE, 2006 – SEPTEMBER, 2008

SR. CSA, FIRSTSOUCRE SOLUTION LIMITED

Worked for Lloyds TSB UK and AOL UK as Sr. CSA.

Mastered knowledge base in Computer Networking along with broadband support. Achieved best Resolution rate, Customer Service consistently. Trained 2 batches for Product training, Communication Skills & Technical Troubleshooting skills.

EDUCATION

2005

HSC, TOLANI COLLEGE OF COMMERCE

Mumbai University

2003

SSC, BOMBAY CAMBRIDGE SCHOOL

Maharashtra Board